

Data Science Group, Institute for Basic Science (IBS), Daejeon 34126, Korea

📕 (+82) 10-8845-2205 | 💌 kdkyum531 @gmail.com | 🧥 kdkyum.github.io | 🖸 kdkyum | 🛅 kdkyum | 💆 @kdkyum531 | 定 Google Scholar

Summary_

I am a physicist passionate about AI and did my PhD in physics at KAIST, Korea. Under professor Hawoong Jeong's supervision, I worked on applications of ML in complex systems and statistical physics. My current research focus is understanding highly complex nonequilibrium systems, such as biological systems, active matter, and others in nature, through stochastic thermodynamics with ML-based approaches.

Education

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, Korea

DOCTOR OF PHILOSOPHY (PHD) IN PHYSICS, ADVISOR: PROF. HAWOONG JEONG

Mar. 2016 - Feb. 2022

• Dissertation: Nonequilibrium Statistical Physics Study using Deep Learning

Seoul National University (SNU)

Seoul, Korea

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (BS) IN PHYSICS WITH A MINOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE & ENGINEERING

2011 - 2015

Experience

Institute for Basic Science (IBS)

Daejeon, Korea

SENIOR RESEARCHER

Mar. 2022 - present

- Hosted by prof. Meeyoung Cha (Chief Investigator).
- Data Science Group, Center for Mathematical and Computational Sciences.

Samsung Electronics

Hwaseong, Korea

MACHINE LEARNING INTERN

Sep. 2017 - Dec. 2017

- Collaborated with Daniel Kim, PhD (Senior Data Scientist).
- Improved anomaly image classification tasks via distributed multi-GPU training methods of Keras & Spark.
- Implemented a distributed image searching framework to detect similar patterns in images through Elasticsearch.

Publication

Transformer needs NMDA receptor nonlinearity for long-term memory

D.-K, KIM, J. KWON, M. CHA, C. J. LEE, NeurIPS-W 2022 (Memory in Artificial and Real Intelligence)

2022

Multidimensional entropic bound: Estimator of entropy production for general Langevin dynamics with an arbitrary time-dependent protocol

S. Lee, D.-K. KIM, J. M. PARK, W. K. KIM, H. PARK & J. S. Lee (Under Review), arXiv preprint arXiv:2207.05961

2022

Inferring dissipation maps from videos using convolutional neural networks

Y. BAE, D.-K. KIM & H. JEONG, Phys. Rev. Research 4, 033094, 🔾 godudrud/CNEEP

2022

Estimating entropy production with odd-parity state variables via machine learning

D.-K. KIM, S. LEE & H. JEONG, Phys. Rev. Research 4, 023051, Akkyum/odd_neep

2022

Spontaneous emergence of music detectors in a deep neural network

G. Kim, **D.-K. Kim** & H. Jeong, *bioRxiv* 2021.10.27.466049, **\(\rightarrow \)** kgspiano/Music (Under Review)

2021

Deep reinforcement learning for feedback control in a collective flashing ratchet

D.-K. KIM & H. JEONG, Phys. Rev. Research 3, L022002, Akdkyum/RatchetDRL

2021

Learning Entropy Production via Neural Networks

D.-K. KIM, Y. BAE, S. LEE & H. JEONG, Phys. Rev. Lett. 125, 140604, 🗘 kdkyum/neep

Multi-Label Classification of Historical Documents by Using Hierarchical Attention Networks

D.-K. KIM, B. LEE, D. KIM & H. JEONG, J. Korean Phys. Soc. 76, 368

2020

Skills

Programming Languages Python*, R, JAVA, Scheme, C, C++ (* skills daily used)

ML Frameworks

JAX*, PyTorch*, Keras, TensorFlow

Distributed Computing Slurm*, Spark, Elasticsearch

Award

2021.8.30 Pre-doctoral Fellow of Physics at KAIST

Daejeon, Korea

Presentation

Working and reference memory in transformers on a navigation task

2022 KIAS CAINS SUMMER WORKSHOP (INVITED TALK)

Sono Belle, Jeju, Korea

Sep. 2, 2022

Deep reinforcement learning for optimal mechanism in active Brownian particles

2022 NONEQUILIBRIUM STATISTICAL PHYSICS OF COMPLEX SYSTEMS (CONFERENCE, POSTER)

KIAS, Seoul, Korea Jul. 25, 2022

Exploring optimal mechanisms in active Brownian particles via deep reinforcement learning

APCTP Workshop for Physics and Machine Learning (Invited talk)

Jeju, Korea Nov. 26, 2021

Methods of estimating entropy production

SEOUL NATIONAL UNIVERSITY STATISTICAL PHYSICS SEMINAR (INVITED TALK)

(Online) Korea Feb. 1, 2021

Deep reinforcement learning for feedback-controlled flashing ratchets

KOREAN PHYSICAL SOCIETY FALL MEETING (CONFERENCE, ORAL)

(Online) Korea Nov. 6, 2020

Discovering wiring patterns of neural networks via backboning

NETSCI2020 (CONFERENCE, ORAL)

(Online) Rome, Italy

Sep. 22, 2020

(Online) Korea

Neural estimator for entropy production

KOREAN PHYSICAL SOCIETY SPRING MEETING (CONFERENCE, ORAL)

Jul. 13, 2020

Quantifying Individual Reputation in Large-scale Historical Documents

QUANTIFYING SUCCESS SATELLITE AT NETSC12019 (CONFERENCE, ORAL)

Burlington, Vermont, USA

May. 27, 2019

Teaching Experience

Physics and AI Winter School

SPECIAL TALK

(Online) Korea

Feb. 24, 2022

General Physics II

TEACHING ASSISTANT

KAIST, Korea

2016 (Fall), 2017 (Spring)

References

Hawoong Jeong

Professor Department of Physics, KAIST Daejeon 34141, Korea

□ hjeong@kaist.edu

Yongjoo Baek

Assistant Professor Department of Physics & Astronomy, SNU Seoul 08826, Korea

✓ y.baek@snu.ac.kr

Junghyo Jo

Assistant Professor Department of Physics Education, SNU Seoul 08826, Korea

☑ jojunghyo@snu.ac.kr